{"qu1":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the number of roots common to the equations <i>x<\/i><sup>3<\/sup> + 4<i>x<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + 5<i>x<\/i> + 18 = 0 and <i>x<\/i><sup>3<\/sup> + 3<i>x<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + 10<i>x<\/i> + 12 = 0. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu2":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A man is 20 minutes late to his office, if he drives at an average speed of 40 kmph and is four minutes early, if he drives at an average speed of 50 kmph. By how much time will he be early \/  late, if he drives at an average speed of 48 kmph?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 minute early\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 minute late\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 minutes late\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu3":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">A regular hexagon ABCDEF is inscribed in a circle of radius 18 cm. Another circle is then inscribed in the hexagon ABCDEF. Now, another regular hexagon is inscribed in the second circle and this process continues indefinitely. What is the sum of the areas (in sq.cm) of all the circles and the hexagons that are formed? <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">(324<\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial Unicode MS;\">&nbsp;<img height=\"6\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAcAAAAGCAYAAAAPDoR2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAACPSURBVBhXJY0hDoUwAEN3MiwJCYYbEBC7AwLBZSZYCGpTE2g8kIDjANNjyeOz\/1TTNq3gh\/eeeZ4xxjBNE9ZanHOIEAJKKfI8p6oq+r4nyzK01oht21J7XVe6ruO+b6SU3yAixpjEsiw0TcNxHNR1nbz0+VGWJcMwcJ4nbduy7\/s\/vK6LoihS6Xme9D2OIy8\/SYKZHNd+DwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"7\" \/>&nbsp;<font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">+ 486 <img height=\"16\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAQCAYAAADwMZRfAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHhSURBVDhPjZPNaxpRFMVHaZB046KzFtJV048g4kJQSNfNzhQRRKgVXNmKoAi6EhEUnIJ1rW6ShX\/A6ELTP8Down0qIooLHUjxE0FPfXde06Z0hv7gMfecy5x57\/JGgA77\/R6SJCESiWiuaDQK3ZDRaIRAIIB+v6+7dEPK5TIKhQJX2uiGxGIx1Ot1rrTRDGHz8Pl8GI\/H3AEajQZKpRKazSZ3VDRD2Dz8fj\/Vq+USFxfvIAgCLBYLPS8v32O73VJfM0SWZSQSCaq\/Fov0oiyrR6sfekxfXV+T1gzJ5\/OoVqtUf7+7ezSbH\/f3FCJJX0hrhgSDQfR6Pa5UFGWG4mFXZ2dvcH7+FovFgvx\/hiwPM\/B6vdhsNtxR+XZzA6vVCrPZDKfLheFwSL6gKArdSrvdjslkQma320UoFKL6T3a7HT1nsxlE8RmcThdpoVarIZPJwGg0IhwOk1mpVJDL5ahmTKdTDAYDrlQinz\/RXBgPx2FBzFytVkilUmi1WrwDfAx8wPHxU6zXa+4Ar1+9xMnJc6ofQubzOUwmE+LxOP1Uv47GuG23cXT0BC9OT5FMJuFwOGAwGA6XTv3Qo8Gm02najdvt5s5vOp0OPB4PbDYb9dvtW975K4QhiiKy2SxX\/wPwE3vRlBEoT9I1AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"17\" \/> ) <\/font> <\/font><\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT2":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">(648<\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial Unicode MS;\">&nbsp;<img height=\"6\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAcAAAAGCAYAAAAPDoR2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAACPSURBVBhXJY0hDoUwAEN3MiwJCYYbEBC7AwLBZSZYCGpTE2g8kIDjANNjyeOz\/1TTNq3gh\/eeeZ4xxjBNE9ZanHOIEAJKKfI8p6oq+r4nyzK01oht21J7XVe6ruO+b6SU3yAixpjEsiw0TcNxHNR1nbz0+VGWJcMwcJ4nbduy7\/s\/vK6LoihS6Xme9D2OIy8\/SYKZHNd+DwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"7\" \/>&nbsp;<font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">+ 972 <img height=\"16\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAQCAYAAADwMZRfAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHhSURBVDhPjZPNaxpRFMVHaZB046KzFtJV048g4kJQSNfNzhQRRKgVXNmKoAi6EhEUnIJ1rW6ShX\/A6ELTP8Down0qIooLHUjxE0FPfXde06Z0hv7gMfecy5x57\/JGgA77\/R6SJCESiWiuaDQK3ZDRaIRAIIB+v6+7dEPK5TIKhQJX2uiGxGIx1Ot1rrTRDGHz8Pl8GI\/H3AEajQZKpRKazSZ3VDRD2Dz8fj\/Vq+USFxfvIAgCLBYLPS8v32O73VJfM0SWZSQSCaq\/Fov0oiyrR6sfekxfXV+T1gzJ5\/OoVqtUf7+7ezSbH\/f3FCJJX0hrhgSDQfR6Pa5UFGWG4mFXZ2dvcH7+FovFgvx\/hiwPM\/B6vdhsNtxR+XZzA6vVCrPZDKfLheFwSL6gKArdSrvdjslkQma320UoFKL6T3a7HT1nsxlE8RmcThdpoVarIZPJwGg0IhwOk1mpVJDL5ahmTKdTDAYDrlQinz\/RXBgPx2FBzFytVkilUmi1WrwDfAx8wPHxU6zXa+4Ar1+9xMnJc6ofQubzOUwmE+LxOP1Uv47GuG23cXT0BC9OT5FMJuFwOGAwGA6XTv3Qo8Gm02najdvt5s5vOp0OPB4PbDYb9dvtW975K4QhiiKy2SxX\/wPwE3vRlBEoT9I1AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"17\" \/> ) <\/font> <\/font><\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">(864&nbsp;<\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial Unicode MS;\"><img height=\"6\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAcAAAAGCAYAAAAPDoR2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAACPSURBVBhXJY0hDoUwAEN3MiwJCYYbEBC7AwLBZSZYCGpTE2g8kIDjANNjyeOz\/1TTNq3gh\/eeeZ4xxjBNE9ZanHOIEAJKKfI8p6oq+r4nyzK01oht21J7XVe6ruO+b6SU3yAixpjEsiw0TcNxHNR1nbz0+VGWJcMwcJ4nbduy7\/s\/vK6LoihS6Xme9D2OIy8\/SYKZHNd+DwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"7\" \/>&nbsp;<font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">+ 129 <img height=\"16\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAQCAYAAADwMZRfAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHhSURBVDhPjZPNaxpRFMVHaZB046KzFtJV048g4kJQSNfNzhQRRKgVXNmKoAi6EhEUnIJ1rW6ShX\/A6ELTP8Down0qIooLHUjxE0FPfXde06Z0hv7gMfecy5x57\/JGgA77\/R6SJCESiWiuaDQK3ZDRaIRAIIB+v6+7dEPK5TIKhQJX2uiGxGIx1Ot1rrTRDGHz8Pl8GI\/H3AEajQZKpRKazSZ3VDRD2Dz8fj\/Vq+USFxfvIAgCLBYLPS8v32O73VJfM0SWZSQSCaq\/Fov0oiyrR6sfekxfXV+T1gzJ5\/OoVqtUf7+7ezSbH\/f3FCJJX0hrhgSDQfR6Pa5UFGWG4mFXZ2dvcH7+FovFgvx\/hiwPM\/B6vdhsNtxR+XZzA6vVCrPZDKfLheFwSL6gKArdSrvdjslkQma320UoFKL6T3a7HT1nsxlE8RmcThdpoVarIZPJwGg0IhwOk1mpVJDL5ahmTKdTDAYDrlQinz\/RXBgPx2FBzFytVkilUmi1WrwDfAx8wPHxU6zXa+4Ar1+9xMnJc6ofQubzOUwmE+LxOP1Uv47GuG23cXT0BC9OT5FMJuFwOGAwGA6XTv3Qo8Gm02najdvt5s5vOp0OPB4PbDYb9dvtW975K4QhiiKy2SxX\/wPwE3vRlBEoT9I1AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"17\" \/> ) <\/font> <\/font><\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">(1296<\/font><font style=\"font-family:Arial Unicode MS;\">&nbsp;<img height=\"6\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAcAAAAGCAYAAAAPDoR2AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAACPSURBVBhXJY0hDoUwAEN3MiwJCYYbEBC7AwLBZSZYCGpTE2g8kIDjANNjyeOz\/1TTNq3gh\/eeeZ4xxjBNE9ZanHOIEAJKKfI8p6oq+r4nyzK01oht21J7XVe6ruO+b6SU3yAixpjEsiw0TcNxHNR1nbz0+VGWJcMwcJ4nbduy7\/s\/vK6LoihS6Xme9D2OIy8\/SYKZHNd+DwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"7\" \/>&nbsp;<font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">+ 1944 <img height=\"16\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAQCAYAAADwMZRfAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAHhSURBVDhPjZPNaxpRFMVHaZB046KzFtJV048g4kJQSNfNzhQRRKgVXNmKoAi6EhEUnIJ1rW6ShX\/A6ELTP8Down0qIooLHUjxE0FPfXde06Z0hv7gMfecy5x57\/JGgA77\/R6SJCESiWiuaDQK3ZDRaIRAIIB+v6+7dEPK5TIKhQJX2uiGxGIx1Ot1rrTRDGHz8Pl8GI\/H3AEajQZKpRKazSZ3VDRD2Dz8fj\/Vq+USFxfvIAgCLBYLPS8v32O73VJfM0SWZSQSCaq\/Fov0oiyrR6sfekxfXV+T1gzJ5\/OoVqtUf7+7ezSbH\/f3FCJJX0hrhgSDQfR6Pa5UFGWG4mFXZ2dvcH7+FovFgvx\/hiwPM\/B6vdhsNtxR+XZzA6vVCrPZDKfLheFwSL6gKArdSrvdjslkQma320UoFKL6T3a7HT1nsxlE8RmcThdpoVarIZPJwGg0IhwOk1mpVJDL5ahmTKdTDAYDrlQinz\/RXBgPx2FBzFytVkilUmi1WrwDfAx8wPHxU6zXa+4Ar1+9xMnJc6ofQubzOUwmE+LxOP1Uv47GuG23cXT0BC9OT5FMJuFwOGAwGA6XTv3Qo8Gm02najdvt5s5vOp0OPB4PbDYb9dvtW975K4QhiiKy2SxX\/wPwE3vRlBEoT9I1AAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"17\" \/> ) <\/font> <\/font><\/font><\/span><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu4":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If <i>f<\/i> (<i>x<\/i>) = 3<i>x<\/i> + 5 and <i>g<\/i>(<i>x<\/i>) = 2<i>x<\/i> + 4, and <i>f<\/i><i> <\/i>(<i>g<\/i>(<i>f<\/i> (<i>g<\/i>(<i>x<\/i>)))) = 335, find the value of <i>x<\/i><i>.<\/i><i>\n<\/i><\/font><i>\n<\/i><\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"6","CORRECT_ANSWER":"6","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu5":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Which of the following cannot be the number of digits in the product of nine eleven-digit numbers?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>99\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>96\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>95\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>90\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu6":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the maximum value of tan<sup>4<\/sup>\u03b8 + sec<sup>4<\/sup>\u03b8 \u2013 2 tan<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8 sec<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>0\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Not defined \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu7":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>7<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Anwar leaves home by car everyday at 4 pm to pick up his son from school and returns home at 6 pm. One day, the school was over at 4 pm and the son, instead of waiting for his father as usual, started walking home from school. Anwar, unaware of this, starts from home as usual and meets his son on the way and returns home with him 15 minutes earlier than usual. If the speed of Anwar\u2019s car is 35 kmph, find the speed (in kmph) of his son.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>8\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu8":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>8<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Anand is the owner of a transport company. He has a total of 30 trucks available for rent every week, from Monday morning to Saturday evening. During a certain week, 50% of the trucks he had rented out during that week were returned on or before Saturday evening. Find the maximum number of trucks that could have been rented out during that week, if he had at least 18 trucks with him on the Saturday evening of that week. Assume that no truck was rented out more than once in that week.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"24","CORRECT_ANSWER":"24","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu9":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>AB is a chord of a circle with centre O. C is a point on the circle such that   <img Width='12' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAMCAYAAABWdVznAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAADnSURBVChTfZExDkRAFIb3OhK1A6i1DuAQDkFE7xBoUJAoqVQKDdFRSLQSwb\/7XnbEZu1+yct7\/8z\/z0wyD7w5juO29n3nLnhcxT+GYeB+BrZt+yo6nbBtG6Zp8vwzIMyO48AwDKzryvo2IMyu60LTNCzLwpq4DRCe50FRFEzTxFqsfwWIMAwhyzK6rmN93fsIEGVZ8sl1XbMW5jMg3kuQSVVVVFXF+mo+A+KGtm2h6zqapmH9C\/7pvu8hSRIsy0JRFMiyjCtNU64kSdjDAXrSPM8IggB5niOOY0RRxF3Mvu9jHMeXHXgCXrgQUr91emgAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  ACB = 30\u00b0. If AB = 4 cm, the area of triangle BOC can be at most\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='23' Height= '15' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABcAAAAPCAYAAAAPr1RWAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJhSURBVDhPnZTBS5pxGMdfFpE3Dy5hSepCqdxJ2iEP2UVxs4OsvyBwVNBQl7o2Ng2cDdwUdddAw3np2KGEDk1wrA6xDqmHINohJXIHzUNC6Xfv+\/hrsfkGww+8vM\/3+\/ze7\/vye5\/35dAl+\/v7WF5eRiQSET1isRi6DhcCMpkMrq+v7zy6Dp+bm8P5+TlT4nQVfnZ2htnZWabupiP84OAH1tfXmRJne3sbPp+PKWBrcxMzMzNwuVw4PMwz95\/wX5UKpFIplEoVc8SJx+NIpVJU+969BcdxsFqteDw2hns9PdjZ+Uq9v8LNJhMtHB83MEccp9OJQqGARqMBhUIBt9vDOoBudARPnlqp\/hPu9bih0z3Ci4UFDA+PMLeTy8tL2O12OjebTdRqNToLHB0dYWDgAZZevyFN4bu73+mJT05+Ivg+gIdDQ9QUI5\/Pw+FwMHXL9PQzylCqVKhWa+RxpdNTaDQaJJNrZCwtvYJGq6VaYG9vD4FAgCkgnU4jGo0y1ebq6grZbBYbGxtQDg7CZDaTzy3w2yDc0WAwQK\/XQy6Xo6+vDxMTRmxtZTA1NUX9mwny+\/308dzQarZY1WYtmaT11WoV3LdcDqurq\/TFhcNhTE4aIZPJ+KeLoVwuo9VqwWaz8ROkpIvn5+dRKpWorvDTpVar+cn5Qlrg08cQhdfr9c45d7mcuN\/fz1SbYrFIFyQSCXi9Xua2t8NonKBePP4ZK8Eg1Xb7c+p3hAt7+nJxkalbLBYLent7EQqFmNOmfnHBT5oHWv49jY7qsLLygf4rAh3hd3F8fAyJRIIcv43\/B\/Ab00aBrRB6PJAAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/>  cm<sup>2<\/sup>.<sup><\/sup><sup><\/sup><sup>\n<\/sup><\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='19' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABMAAAAfCAYAAAAFkva3AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAK9SURBVEhLzZVLSBtBGMej4iVBQcEE04v22BgLibUlBy21D0NbaHtr6i3agyUqNAVbbaSxBG1qGkgVLPaYeNJTvIgBqwdjMMGD4APBiL3kgSaKB+Pj353JWCLuI9BS+oOB7\/\/t7C+7M9ldGfLE7XbD6fzMEj95yUKLiygsLMTDR49Zhx9J2c+dHZSXl0NZUYG79+6zLj+SMm1NDSwdHXjV3o66G\/Wsy4+o7I31Naqrr9L6ZWsr6m\/eorUQgrLAzAxkMhnGxr5jeXkZzc0PcE2jofXx8TGbdRFB2fveXpSWlkKpVKKkpATFxcUoKiqCWn0FiUSSzbqIoOzw8BDJZBKxWIyOZ0+foLb2OuLxOE5PT9msi0huwDkvTM+h09exxE\/esu3tbWxsbLDET96yfPiPZaFQCC6XC0NDQ380iEMWiUTg9Xr\/yvj3azYyMoLOzk7BYbVacXR0JC3b2tqC0WhEOBwWHScnJ9KyyclJ2Gw2lsSRlNntdoyPj7MkjqTMbDZjdXWV1mdnZ5ienobP58Pa2jrt5SIqS6fTMJlMyGQySO3t4XZjI33HqVQqFBQUwOP5ymZmEZXNz8\/DYrHQ2v2F+1NyoqWlMM1vu7tp3kulaCaIyoaHh7lf99A6kUhwt7ZGa8KnwUHIFQrsHxywjoSsq6sLc3NzLGWZmvJDq9XSq\/J6fayb5beMvD0nJiawsrJCM1mnlpYW7O7u0nzOj9lZOBwONHLrp+G+CdFolB3JkTmdTii4y9bpdDRvbm7SnRRin9sccnUf7P2skyNLcQtJFpxMCAaDCAQC6OvrY0eBb6OjaGtrYwnZx4eba+\/\/yDo8a2YwGNDQ0ICBgQF62+cQGTn5XU8P\/H4\/mpruQC6XYz3nVX5JtrCwQE+qqqqiX6VcyM6qKytRVlYGPfdxIXeQyyUZgTzYer2epXwBfgFq2hvhUuoe7QAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>   cm<sup>2<\/sup>.<sup><\/sup><sup><\/sup><sup>\n<\/sup><\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 cm<sup>2<\/sup>.<sup><\/sup><sup><\/sup><sup><\/sup><sup>\n<\/sup><\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of these\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu10":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If N is a natural number and N! ends with <i>m<\/i> zeros, then the number of zeros that (5N)! ends with is always\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>5<i>m<\/i> + 1.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='12' Height= '28' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAAwAAAAcCAYAAABVo158AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAILSURBVDhPzZTPT9pgGMdL5eQS4jLdBQWBHQiYTEjUuMTihiZbdmIlLuEPYP6YJx26THeYB8eO+gdw04M7OdyBQIJk4zTKPwDEuYQzQk1IJHzXvn3WtcTM3bZP8qZ9vk8\/6dumTzkQW1tv8G5nh6rf7O\/vYXv7LVWALoz5fbDwPNLpE0o0nj55DJfLQ5VB8Pt8sFqt4Pk+VKtVSoH5uTCczlGqDMKw3Y54PA6P243JqSlK\/yAMDd7B7vskymUJHMchmfzA8rnwo+uFu0ODWF9\/xc6XFl8w6fz8B6LiMzgcTparmIQ1EtrtNhwjI5iefoD5cBgezz2Wq1wrqBS\/fmF3sVgsGA8EKTUI1j4ei0srVGm83txk0qjLTYlBWFlexsHhIVUanasrrK6+RCKxQYlB+Fv+RyGTyUAURUQikRtXLBYDV6\/XkcvlkM1mb1z5fP5fPPSlLKPRaOir1WpRR8MkfD87g12ZC5vNpq\/Q7EPqapiEj0dH7Ns5Pv6EYrGIQqGAkiRRV8MkbCQS+rff7XbZsReToE5Xf\/8tBIMBtjUhFEKtVqOuhkl4vrCg7HkWpZKkjGoZgfH7GFYGSZYv6YoeoZdfQ5Q++UyJQZCV15lKpVCpVCgBpNI3TTD8q3SheXHBmjNCCJ1Oh2XRqIiBgdtoNpusVjFtqXB6Cq\/Xi4mJSQiCAL9\/DFXTQwM\/Aa2UU\/cy1O3VAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  + <i>m<\/i><i>.<\/i>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>N + <i>m<\/i><i>.<\/i> \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Cannot be determined\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu11":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are two kids both of whom weigh less than 10 kg and have integral weights (in kilos). Weight of the lighter kid is equal to the cube root of the product of the weights of the two kids. If the digit representing the weight of the lighter kid is placed to the left of the digit representing the weight of the heavier kid, we get half the weight of their mother. Similarly, if we place the digit representing the weight of the heavier kid to the left of the weight of the lighter kid, we get the weight of their father. If the father weighs 15 kgs more than the mother, then what is the weight of the lighter kid?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>4 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 kg\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu12":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Let g(x) = min(11 \u2212 x, x + 4). The largest possible value of g(x) is \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='18' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAiCAYAAABStIn6AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAItSURBVEhL7ZZNiKlRGMd9hXxMTRYWZGclkcXsp2Yho2SDnZQVNkqStZIsx5RZzGqibGZqVrJSsrCkpEgKWVhQFoTyn3uOMybMi2bu7t5fPTnPc45fb8853oMHDnK5HILB4LcxGAzYqi84Rbe3t9BqtbDZbDTu7+9hNBqh1+vZin04RS6XC81mk2VbPB4PUqkUy\/bhFM3nczbaUq\/XoVKpMJ1OWWUfTtEhDocDfr+fZcdcJCLNVSgU6HQ6rHLMRSKv10ubf4qzoslkAoFAgEqlwirfc1YUi8VgMBhYxs1JEXkaoVCIfD7PKtycFMXjcchkMqzXa1bh5qSoVquh0Wiw7DRne3Qp\/0Xn+XuiRCJBT+5vg1cul\/Hw8PDr+Jd2bTabIZlMot\/vs8oXo9EImUwGoVAIgUAAxWKRzRyIstksNBoN+Hw+xuMxq255f3+HSCSCz+fD29sbotEoeDweyK4TdiKyIBKJwG634\/r6GqvVis1seXl5wd3dHcu23NzcQKlU0vFO1O126Sf5glQqxWKxoPkpnE4nxGIxHR\/16Onpib7MzonIvSeRSBAOh2n+Y5Hb7abX9+dF+iPR4+Mjrq6u0Ov1WOUHokKhQHvYbrdZZcuR6Pn5GXK5HMvlklW+aLVa9EnI7\/MTso7s8JEonU7T83Io2mw29G\/N57khObmurFYrPag70XA4xOvrK8xmM90NcuCq1SqbBUqlEr3jLBYLTCYTDZ1OB7Va\/WcW+AA3Kn0wPKZCBwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/> \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='18' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAiCAYAAABStIn6AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAIrSURBVEhL7ZY7aCpBFIYFC40imCaIVmKljXaBBKy0EywstNHCTmwsBAkWGgJiFG2sLETQUmx8VmKlhWgh2ImICFbxEURCIuQPMzuR7N2YyM3tcj8Yds+Zw7fjOpxZEf5gu90ikUhgPp+zjJCHhwfEYjEsl0uWAXiicrkMk8mEi4sLvL6+siyfQqEAvV4PrVbLMhwHkdfrRTAYhM1mw\/n5OV5eXtgMx2azgcvlws3NDcxmM3Q6HZvhOIgmkwm9FotFSKVSPD090fgdEk+nU3ofj8fpqj8ieEfZbBYymUwg+kg0GoVKpWIRx28S5XI5yOVyPD8\/s4yQu7s7qNVqFnEIRPf39xCLxV+uKBAI4OzsjEUcB1G\/30cmk4FGo4FIJILb7UapVMJqtWIVQLfbRSqVovuM1Ph8PrqJyeoPouFwiGq1ilarhU6ng1qthkajgfV6zSq4h1UqFbTbbVpD6pvNJt28gp\/2t\/wXfc+\/E5F9cX19\/eMhqtfriEQiPx6\/9V8bjUZIp9Pw+\/30ulgs2IyQoyKPx0MbXDKZRD6fh9FopA1\/PB6zCj5HRVarlR6U7xABaR2hUIhl+Jz8jh4fHw896DNOFpEmR0SDwYBl+JwkIquRSCQIh8MsI+Qk0dXVFex2O4s+51sR+RawWCwsOs6XotvbWxgMBuz3e5YBdrsdu+NzVNTr9aBQKDCbzVgG9EBwOp0s4nNU5HA4oFQqcXl5Sb+ZyCAblJxpQoA37kN8Io8Sw+oAAAAASUVORK5CYII=\"\/> \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9999999'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='18' Height= '35' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAiCAYAAABStIn6AAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJ3SURBVEhL7ZYxSGpRGMcdFMIQJB1cgsZsEKJFHKS5RBwUGtocUiIsSIIWM6q5QQgrlBKMdNBFN9GGIHFw1KAItwxdNIzU+D\/O10m73uvL93pb7weHy\/d9x5\/3nnvvd64MEiSTSVSrVR71ub6+RjqdRiqVohGNRnFwcEA1gahYLMJqtUKn0+H19ZVn+8zOzmJiYgJarZaGRqOBw+GgWk+0vr6O5eVlzM3N0YROp8Mr77BYr9cjm83i8fGRBjvr5+dnqvdEV1dXdDw\/P8fY2BheXl4o\/oCJZmZmcHt7yzNCRGt0fHwMpVIpKZqensbd3R263S7P9hGJgsGgpOjt7Q0GgwGLi4swmUx0mVtbW715I4sY7GzYDWHHRCIBmUwGm81GtT8SDbKxsUGyZrMpFp2enmJ8fFzy9g9ydnZGoqenJ7Ho8PAQCoVCtKCxWAxut5tH7zidTsjlcrTb7b6oXC7Tkzo1NUX\/sra2hkwmg0ajQXV2pizv9\/spv7+\/D5VKhVAoRPWe6ObmBuFwGJFIBPF4nH54cXGBWq1G9VarhVwuh+3tbfh8Puzs7AieKdGl\/S3\/RV\/z70RHR0ewWCzfHrLLy0usrq5+e\/zUu3Z\/f0+td3NzEycnJ6jX67wiZqjI5XLR2727u4tAIECtdXJyEg8PD3yGkKEis9lMLeODUqlEbYS9\/VIMFQ3ua6wvMdHKygrPCBl5sdk2zkT5fJ5nhIwkYs2dbQher5dnxIwkYuu1sLDAI2m+FLF9a35+nkfD+a1ob2+PtunPWxPr3VIMFRUKBXqOKpUKz4C+iZaWlngkZKjIbrdDrVbDaDTSdxEbbME9Hg+f8RngF9\/RZd4Kk2zLAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/> \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu13":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>9<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If <i>p<\/i> and <i>q<\/i> are the roots of the quadratic equation <i>p<\/i><i>x<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>p<\/i><i>x<\/i> + <i>q<\/i> = 0, then \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>q<\/i> < 0.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>q<\/i> > 0.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>q<\/i> \u2264 0.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><i>q<\/i> = 0.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu14":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>How many positive integers upto 3528 are co-prime to 42?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"1008","CORRECT_ANSWER":"1008","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu15":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>4<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>5<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Eight straight lines, no two of which are parallel and no three of which pass through any common point, are drawn on a plane. The total number of regions (including finite and infinite regions) into which the plane would be divided by the lines is\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"37","CORRECT_ANSWER":"37","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu16":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,R0lGODlh9QAeAPcAAP\/\/\/wAAACMjI6enp4mJiUdHR8PDw93d3f\/bkDoAZrb\/\/\/\/\/25A6AAAAOpDb\/zoAAGa2\/\/+2ZgAAZrZmAAA6kNv\/\/\/\/\/tmYAOjoAOtuQOgBmtmlpaWYAAAA6ZmY6OpC2kGYAZpBmkDqQ2zo6kJBmAJA6OpA6ZmY6kJAqFwAAMgBmkJDb25BmZpCcZra2ZrZmZjpmtmZYOmZmtrZmOgAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACwAAAAA9QAeAAAI\/wABCBxIsKDBgwgTKlzIsKHDhxAjSpxIsaLFixgzatzIsaPHjyBDihxJsqTJkyhTqlzJsqXLlzBjypxJs6bNmzgvBtjJc2dOgz2DCv1JVGWAogqPIl0aUynTgk6fSkUZdWrVqVhHXn261aKAngIACBiwkEABggaOHghgYONYjGvZEkSQQMFHunYBLGAQoIGDg0cRPNgJwSHejhF2SsgrmDBQgYkDLBbYOEBhh28jmkWrVq7GzBYHnC14GLHkvBMKR6BQAaiFC38RYPjLsLTGwxk0AHgdezZUALh18wbuuyFogWPXbthJFgCBnRtGA4grQDlzgQN2ShfoWQABAMt3Hv8QO2Bt27TYtRvMHuAs+7Bz6+7mcFqgBfodPNBuOKHBB\/kWgJAXQgFEoJtAqRm0QAitDXTYffXNF0B++z2El4EDJUhQVRceCICGDB1HnnLOhZXWeAJshx6JBJgYAIrfDbTBd2sdMAB8BWwwolzonShWjAKZ9yMANxp02AQiALBaa0gq6VdEhyEwAgl9VchdQcMVtGCDlMnX5JIfJhnBkxHlhiVsGxpkJkFZhthTW8nxeNRmzqnY2Xlz6kgkfNiFJVpBG+gYJ57O6VnkQHQWeWh8CgRoF2+O6lWClbXJJ1hhUnJ55UB7Jakgg4xGCqmAklKqkGBkCtTpbw4+kKpeDHj\/alxzAw0KAHrRYWfndHKCBxZUB2zQ3FfQ7UhoeDvxCd5oiirbpQKHLTBppqVCaekIrQ3nlFP3yaoqXz0diFe002JbbURZdjuQUlely4G3IdKKXHm90kmnQCvWq+dBBWQ3Hp2BkgeAvggl6qezwNUlKmyRSuvAAibkNRRpAJ6QLWw+bXppQluGSuqodi2AQpXcBZVQghuXvGlBKD9w2UMi2povnLsK2eOLyxb03Gi5kvhWAGQtdyvOuQ4kpAA6Luqgl2KyFqaTDkQw2cALlYayuVRTnTJCHS9t15dOf5lC1Jd1paTTvG29btZgpu2yRDHTSyiR0G038Iu90h0Awms1xEddkW+xJ7TeCLPHLMIP0jc1hCqUsEIILEhctXwSTk21UhkE9TKnoHpdeV6Ml9DC1GYDkDnJp\/NUdlSnP5m6Y7W2lZVLdLkAwQt2lQ5RxiKNC0PWGek+u0177eTX6boF5qqpDwlPUfF9xeCABTJovbxFzg9PFO5UzxC1hzmh+tdR3mOo\/fkYORXB5kipzz768DOUsVLUc5V1\/fHn3zz9pC7Fk339058Ak6KUCewEfEUp4AEHyEACDS97DYygBCdIwQp+JCAAOw==\" style=\"width: 245px; height: 30px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">40.5 <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20.5\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>3.625\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>55.5\r\n<\/font>\r\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu17":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\"><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices. <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<span><font style=\"Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;\"><font style=\"font-family:Arial;\">If <i>a<\/i>, <i>b<\/i><i> <\/i>and <i>c<\/i> are three distinct non-zero real numbers satisfying the equations <i>a<\/i> &minus; <img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAdCAYAAACnmDyCAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAK4SURBVEhL3ZVLTBNRFIYLhoILKIYErWmTIjQthgTDEjQCFRKCNKwIRgTfj42iG0wUV0iEqgtgIWxxBW4oBa10IyQlXQANlCILGiyF4AJLC1Ysj987h+vglEcIJMb4J5PpOX\/vN\/fMvfeMDBFqaWlGXd1zHu1f20DatDRcqazi0f4lAc3NzUImk+FNaxuGhoYwPj7OnS2tra1hcHAQw8PDPLMpCcjW10cgrVaLjIwMREVF4f6Dau4C\/f2fkJp6Cnq9HscSE5GdnYP5+a\/kSUCNDQ0Eamw00ZObm5oodk98xreFBchjYnDn7j3yXC4XedUPH9FYCehicTE0mhQesVJnN0u19PTgRX09oqOPYGXlJ3eBzo4OOBwO+i2CVlfDSFQo8ORpLc8Ak5OTBOrutuDc2RzkGy5wZ7tEkGdqigZ1dL7jGYileb0zUKtUuHb9BncA19gYTCYTAsEgxSLI3NVFg8rLL1Hsm5nB0bg4VFZdpTg\/Lw8qtRrr6+tYXl5m2yQVSuVJhEIh8kXQ45oa6HR65OaeR1ZWFpKSklBSYkQ4vEq+m22FFI2GVlTNgOnppzHFqvgtEeTz+eD3+2lFzGYzBgYGuLOl72wmFosFNpuNZvanRNBh9Q+CFtiOdTqdGBkZOfA1OjoKmdVqRWlpKYxG44GvsrKy\/\/pl8\/uh9fdAwUAAdrudLbMTGxsbPLtde4LaWltxPDmZWqtwUDMzM+F2T3BXql1BY2yTyeVyaruChMOcEB+PyxUVFEdqzxlNT0\/D4\/HQzu3t7aWGf\/PWbe5KtSvoPRsolKLT6VBQUACDwQAZ+6q0t7\/l\/5BqR1BgcRGxsbGoYt1xaWmJch+tH6iDunb41gnaESS0WWHQy1evKfZ6v7CXrUJCgoK11h+Ui9SupT2rrcUJpZIOZVFREQoLC1mpZ7gbKeAXA5YMlHMhlH0AAAAASUVORK5CYII=\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"18\" \/> = <i>b<\/i> &minus; <img height=\"27\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAbCAYAAABxwd+fAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAKxSURBVEhL3ZVPTNJhGMeZBwlhrD\/WobL4l\/2ZabbpVDjYltxSS1tetIjqIGQHWdKtcqhtsuEfDgLGyWbpPTecm23o7JS6CTQPNrjgAXVDJgh8e3l9R\/2QnwdPrc\/27vc+z\/fhu\/d9fr89CJCDx+OBwWCga2hoGIlEgilAKpWE3W6n2suuLqz5fEwBOEZ9FguKiopgNpthHRyEQqFAe3sHU4GHra0oL6+A1WpFXW0tSkouIbK1RbWsUSwWg16vx+TkZ5YBLL29EAgOSt6\/e0v34XCYxqFgEFKpFBMTn2jMOVEoFILNZkN3dzd0Oh2U5ETXrt8gV0rj3NliPGhpYZUHbG9vI5lM0n3WaGrqC4SFhWi424DXPT1wuVyQSCR49vwFYru79DRjYw5WfZiskUqlRG2dmkXAJrlCQUEBxj+6ybUPjJyucaYCr0izG5uasb+fcyKNWo0zxcXwkTcxNzcHpVJJf+yZnaX6zbIyyORyrKysYHRkmGr9Ax+oliFrtL6+jpqaGshkMvrss\/RBo9Fgfv4b1X9tbOBOfT15UyWQE8PMp\/E3nGZn2NnZYbv8ZPR0Os2iPxwyOi7\/oJHf74fT6YTD4Tj2crvdEHi9XnSRb8JoNB57mUym\/7rZ7JkXn28NWq0WP5aXWYafI43soyNsBm2yDD9HGrW1PcJlmRyrq6uYnp5GkAwzPo40ul1ZiRMiEaqrq8mYUUEsFmNhcZGpXHiNIpEIhEIhKipuIRqNkimZgoqMljq1hlVw4TVaWPDS\/nydmWEZ4MnjDpw8dZpFXHiNBvr7ISL\/KPF4nGWA+81NOH\/hIou48Bo1Nd4jE1HBIpAZlIKE9Eine8oyXPIaZQZX6RUVvZo\/EKC5N+YeGgcCP2mcS16j+N4erpaWorOzE1VVVXTEZsbr0tJ3VpEL8BsZ53O3kAyvPwAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"18\" \/> = <i>c<\/i> &minus; <img height=\"30\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABIAAAAdCAYAAACnmDyCAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAK5SURBVEhL3ZVfSJNRGMZnMzBMSMd2X+m22FabGiwNp0YFUi4SES9qMzChgrzIyMvqIiUv7MorKUsy14V2J6bixCvNpuTEEkyEmdNh6jb3x82n872dVlO\/QoWIHjjsfd73fL8dzvm+90iwA9na21FTcxcbGxs881M7Apny8mDKL+AuXltAnsVFtLa2orm5GU7nBM8Ca2trSEpKwh22ojednbDZbAiFQry6CdTW9hIpKSkwGAzIycmhBx83NFBtfPwDEhISoJArYDKZqGY0noKf\/YGgGMjn88Gg1+N2dTXPANcqrEhOPkixrf0VJBIJ6urryb8fGSHf8vwF+bgVra6uYnBwEJ0dHWhqasLJ7Gyo1ceoduvmDchkMqyvR8ivh8MEuldbSz4Gejc8DKVSSaOoqAhVVVWQSqWorLxOdbVKiStXLRQLWlpaItCjuu8rjIEy2b7odMcRjUbJ+\/1+Aj191kJeKt2H+w8eUizoNdtsAeRwjJKPgY4eOYwTegPFLpcLp3NzaaJzYgIfJycp1mi08Hq9mJmZQWrqIZjNl2i+oBjobXc3ZGlpUKlU0LNNLy0thUKhwKepKXoRtVodrBYL0tPTIZfLUWw2ix+\/x+PB0NAQvszPk19ZWUGYbapwooFAgHJjY2Ps\/XJS\/KviQHvRPwiam5tDX18fent7dz3sdjskPT09KC8vR1lZ2a6HhZ3m\/7zZ\/HfP+nsgodEPDAzQEQeDQZ7dqt+CRh0O+oiFIXzAGRkZmGSdYDuJgpaXv1KruFxSgkgkgoWFBWolFy4W8xnxEgU9aWykB390AkFdXV3o77dzFy9R0PlzZ6FUqbn7s0RBOq0G+QWF3AGzs7OoZzeI2+3mmXiJgiqsVnZ3HWCt1Ud9PN+Uh8TE\/dT8tpMoKBgM4ExhITKzsthFaGT9XI\/p6c+8ulnAN93rB7AprQyuAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\" style=\"vertical-align:middle;\" width=\"18\" \/> , <i>b<\/i> would be equal to <\/font> <\/font><\/span><\/p>","OPT1":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,\" style=\"width: 41px; height: 43px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT2":"<p>\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,\" style=\"width: 51px; height: 40px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT3":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,\" style=\"width: 55px; height: 38px;\" \/><\/p>","OPT4":"<p style=\"vertical-align:middle;\">\r\n\t<img alt=\"\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,\" style=\"width: 45px; height: 43px;\" \/><\/p>","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu18":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>On their birthday, Ram and Shyam, a pair of twins, were gifted a large packet of chocolates, containing chocolates of four different flavours. They started eating the chocolates alternately, one chocolate at a time. What should be the minimum total number of chocolates that both of them together should eat, before it can be said that at least one of them has certainly eaten at least four chocolates of a single flavour?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>21\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>26\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>20\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>25\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu19":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>In how many ways can seven friends be seated in a row having 35 seats, such that no two friends occupy adjacent seats?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><sup>2<\/sup><sup>9<\/sup>P<sub>7<\/sub>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><sup>2<\/sup><sup>9<\/sup>C<sub>7<\/sub>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><sup>2<\/sup><sup>8<\/sup>P<sub>7<\/sub>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><sup>2<\/sup><sup>8<\/sup>C<sub>7<\/sub>\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu20":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>1<\/i><i>6<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>0<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A shopkeeper purchased six identical toys at the same price. He sold exactly one of the six toys on each day for the next six days. If the profit he earned on a day was double the profit he earned on the previous day, and the profit earned on the first day was 8%, then by approximately what percentage is the total cost of the six toys less than their total selling price?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>45%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>60%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>75%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>90%\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu21":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>1<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The cost of the feed for 30 cows and 40 buffaloes for 20 days is Rs.3400. If the cost of the feed for 20 cows for 40 days is Rs.2400, find the cost (in Rs.) of the feed for 40 cows and 20 buffaloes for 10 days.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"1600","CORRECT_ANSWER":"1600","UNIT":"Rs.","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu22":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A milkman mixed a certain quantity of milk with water and sold one-third of the mixture. He then added pure milk and water to the remaining mixture. The quantities of the milk and water added were half and one-third, respectively, of the initial quantity of the mixture. The ratio of milk and water now is the reverse of what it was initially. Find the original ratio of milk and water.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>2 : 5\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1 : 2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>6 : 7\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>7 : 9\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu23":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>2<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>3<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Ajay has a collection of <i>n<\/i> books. If the number of ways in which he can select at least one of the books is 2047, what is the number of ways in which he can select exactly two books?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>11\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>45\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>10\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>55\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu24":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'><b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If 1 + <i>a<\/i> + <i>a<\/i><sup>2<\/sup> + <i>a<\/i><sup>3<\/sup> + \u2026\u2026\u2026. + <i>a<\/i><sup>p<\/sup> = (1 + <i>a<\/i>) (1 + <i>a<\/i><sup>2<\/sup>) (1 + <i>a<\/i><sup>4<\/sup>) (1 + <i>a<\/i><sup>8<\/sup>), find the value of <i>p<\/i>.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"15","CORRECT_ANSWER":"15","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu25":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If <i>a<\/i>, <i>b<\/i>, <i>c<\/i> and <i>d<\/i> are distinct positive real numbers, then   <img Width='123' Height= '31' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAHsAAAAfCAYAAADHorIzAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAz0SURBVGhD7VsHVFTXFrX3niKoARVjEqPGEgX1qzGIYCyoiBVs2AXF2BWsGBEbMRol+bbEig1LYkFiF0tUQFGKsUdsqKBYg\/ufc+Y+hpkBs5IfJ47JXust7r7nvXn33XNPuYUcMEJycjLWr9+A58+fq5qXi9OnT+Onn3YrZojr168jLCxMMfPg7t27WLt2rWKmCF0TitTUVMVeXTx8+BBrqK3p6emqBjBR9ogRIxAdHaOYeTCg\/wAkJiYqpsdQX1\/ExycoZj7M\/XIuli37TjE9QhYuxMoVqxR79bF8+XLMnj1HMSNlfzV3Lnx9hypmPkRFRaFho0Z48uSpqgECp03D2LHjFDMvfvvtNzRo0ABR0dGqBjhy5AiaN\/9MMctBM6dmCA\/fJeUMZT99+gTvv\/c+fdRRVWNeNG7cGN99\/72U0x48wLuV3kVs7BnhGh4\/fqxKLwePHj1SJWDK5Mno0KGjYoBr69aYHjRDMfPjj3w7f4cWhhcvXoQmTT6Vcoayw3fuhJWVNZ4+e6ZqzIuRI4bDiUYhY+OGDbCxsZWyhvZubujWvYdifz28evVEa9c2igEHDxxA6dKl8fjJE6SmpKBkyZI4cfKkkpoX\/fv1RctWrRV7MfzGjUV98krp6TplJyYmSNvT0h7qlT1ksA+qVauumPmxYsVyFC5cRMp9envBwaGelBnPnj1F\/nz58MW0QFXz1+OtN99E7z59FaPkMCkJuXLlRnRMDPbs3o28efMhJeXvScysSr8Nb5\/Bir0Y1apWhYtLc8VAofExihQpgp3kyjOUXc\/BHm3atlNMh31796J3797w9PREcHAwuXp9TDVGeHg4zp8\/r1jWiCLLGDBgADw8PCTjz4zDkZHIkSMHLl68BAf7uvDs1l1JgISEeOr4XJRP+KJbt27w8\/fH\/fv3ldQUB8gqY2JOKZY1Yige9+3bB\/2pPQcPHkTu3LmxatVqJaVOIrdZvFgxcoNLEDxnDlm5lcRyDecooeQEktszZswYmjncUBLg1q2b8PMbJ\/02a\/bsF3pLHkhxcXGKmeLGjRvIlzcvtbUvevbsKQn07du3lRQ4\/8sv8Pb2Fj0dOnQIxYsXQ9CMmUpKIHdesUIFTJo0Wa\/s99+rjO49eioGzJo5Uzp\/woSJWLp0KUqVKokuXT2U1BRtXF0RGpr9lGVT2EbkI+vk35s+fbr89iLqSA3x8XFSFxl5GB9WqQKfwfqRvGbNapE5OjbFggULUKxoUThnGr3G6N+vH2bMmKWYKSKpU\/Lnzw\/\/8eMxNSAAxUipuUjZcXHx6g4dypUti2nkTcbT4KpY0U7VAvv37ZX28KD9nvIM+7p1YUc5BsfJq1euwNraCu7uHbBo0SLkpkHauUtX9aQpPLp2RUjIt4qZImIXWSS9y97eQb6d21T7449Fxi66RIkS8PHxwZdkjG+UKoWcOXNi3\/79ItdQu3YtDPL20Su7SOFC6NW7j2LAkiVLsHr1GsWAbp4esC1fQTFT9PbyQkTET4oZ4mFamlhJf5piaWjxWXMMGeKrGBB39qx81Lx58\/H2W2+R1ehnBUOHDEGhQoXx4EGa8OXUwXxvcvId4cbwGzeO2r9UMUOwddra2MA9U\/L1SeNGKFq0mEkS9E65cujRsxc6dewAO7tKqpaVvY8GbJBiwOpVq6Q97Pnc2rU1uJdnFRySsvOKvvRtxl4uM6Z9MVW8TlLSdeHhO3fIu27evEntbox69RtIPaNrly6k7Fxk+cmqRoe6deqg+Wct9MouQ6ORP0wDu5aRI0fSCHVHmzZtUJJGUIeOnZRUh+3btyEwMFCuWjVrkkvrLuVZs2YbuNm9e\/ZIA6Oi9FMZY5w9e0buCQvbhArlbTF48BAlgfx2Zq+yeVOY3JvZdR4iV6y1pVHDhnClZEvjvDij4fjPP8uzR48dUzVAq5Yt0LBhI8X0YCsaOWo0Bg0cYGDZd5KTyeKniWW3bNmKvOJ7qPRuZVlsyZsnD2bS978Iu8l1a21zsLeXrJ\/L7PHu3DEcwC7OzcSjaeDv5PbvpIQ6J\/3dtHmLkug8WuaBpqF2rVrw8OymV3bNGjUyOpRjGLtcf\/\/xEgdiY08Lnz0nWOQajh07Sta\/Wq6G\/\/kPhg8fLmVegeIVHA3r1oZKA7UR94xGOf9u5ns0yz516rQ0rh\/FUsajRw9RsGBBLCZPo2HM6FGUzBU2mCrFxsZmtKVlixYU33pl8Mwd+N2ypRL\/791LUTUQSx8xYqRiepQtUwZzgr9E0PTAjNkBx0seBO3JTe8iF3vu3DlKbKvCza29JEP8DVt\/+FHuZfD8PPNgY\/C6gta2pk2bYuDAgRk8NdUwF7GiGcG0wOmKQdx1YUq41q1bJ+86f\/6CkgB1yL137txFMT1q1qyBz4cN1yu7U8eOsHdwkPJ4fz\/kyZNXyoxlFLP5hw8fPqJqTNGLkgdt8m6MH7ZulecvX74ifMoUShaI37hxUzhj165wUUIaDYB2bdvAsamT1MfF6QYBx3rGfbKePOTW\/MdPEJ4Vxo4eTfFysWKGiIjQxcAotUq4XnXa5i1bhWt48OC+DLIfftyGDevXoUCBglJ\/9Mhhuf\/mrVvCuX3sZud+NU84y7Rc5Ii6d\/v2HcKzwmCKt2vXrlPMEEnXrsnz\/VT4e56eLnF56NDPZbbAsm3btovswIH9wheGfCM8A5RHWFtZ4Ztv\/6tX9kIK\/naVdC6AM+MCBQqgByVsgwYNolFtIz\/0omVU9\/btabStV8wQ7N54SlCXEplBgwbSNCYvvdwwKVnw9XxUoiSHMWvmDFStWk3KiynJ4WTqgw8+INc+WH6nXv36ZEVPRJ4VvKnNc4y8kAaOyw3oeXbL7ImsqCP42y5cvKju0OECzSzYe1y7loQLF7hchLLs27hLXsLW1gaNG38imXH16tUNOrlnjx6UzL4hmTonT716eUl9duD7sxuYm8LCaCDlQeXKlUUP9cgYeXp8\/\/4DkfNCzxs0ZRw2bBgq2dlJO45RmMoMXiMoXrw44hMS9cq+evUqjQBr3KDAzzh54gQmT54kUw9OBiIiInArU8pvDN7Q4PuyA7\/06\/nzMXHiRJzMYnGiS+dOlLDpkrLEhARyoWUl7ifEx+MEtYU7nJ\/lmcHvIYGev0JZcXbg8DFv3jwZELxKt2\/vPoMNAwYnXR99VEMxoAoNtg0bN0o5iawqKCiIYvMseQ\/HUX6nBnax3NYtW\/TxNDucpfDFAyorXLxwQcLAr7\/+St5wChYuDKFETz+N4zZ\/S0YTSLGew9ie3XtMjICnzxUqVJRyhrIZbSkRCzF2A2YAN7pWzVqIPaNfHnVxdsbKlX\/fpoMnJV8crzUEUYd6UpJjaRhOVj+KkkyGgbI5SXKiWHmPrNCcYIs33vRg63du5ow0mraZGzEx0Wjbtq2BlbD7b05z+6y80quKS5cuoUWLlpSg3hVuoGwGT+JDQkIUe\/lgF+U3zk8xQ2ylxG7p0mWKmQ\/+fn4G0zoNnFX7+fkr9urji6lTDVbnchw\/fhyTJk2SGMMXz\/V4RWbChAkZdS\/z4kTG398fAQEBJjKtLcb1L\/PipU9OePjdxjKuY9nYsWNNZK\/a5UcDlpeXObdgzusCJsrmK6uOf1kXJx58ZSXjdpmzLXz93jtZZtxfr+Jl\/B2ibGXh\/+IfgH+V\/Q\/Ca69szqJ56\/XZM\/325J\/B5cuXDbYWLRGvvbKDg+fIjlbmdfg\/ClYyrygu+RtmBn8lXntlu7ZuBXt7\/amXPwNtPfxFu3aWgNdC2bwr17lzZzg5OcHFxQVhmzZJPR8m4DXjOnXqooO7uxxq3JxpS\/AazfH5BAjvPPE27unTsUoCmbo4OjrC29tH9sf\/X+\/wKsDilc3r6Gx1Xbt6yBr61IApwhMSE5GamiLut0qVD7Fjxw45Z8eyi5cuyVp9mTLWaNfODZGRkahXzwGFChfBI4rxvE7\/zjs2stXr4+0tzzRp4qjeaLmweGVzPA0NDZUynwb5+dgxUc4pstIjh3XuV9ua5WSNOW9bTpk8SU6\/aOC9ed6TXrNadwSKDxoyeLmWue\/Qz4VbMixe2UlJ12SlqFXLVmR9TVCjRg3ky59fFDs9MBBW1tbqTt1WK58J4+NWH9euDQ8PTyXRg0+2lq+gP36VQh4gV056Zo1uQFkyLFrZvFHBMZmPzvJWIVs2K8vGtrzIm7s4o5mzi5QZ+\/bqjkdFR0fDrmLFjAMRjLCNG8WdOzV1RFN1fp2hHQqIizc8jGiJsGhlp9y7J4pYsWKl8DNnzqAgxWjtnwnKlS1jYNl88OET9d8RfLzWlZIyhnYkavnyFfCnZExz78+fp8O+bh0UL1Ey2wODlgSLd+OjR4+SUyx8ksPNzU1OjgQETBVZ9WrVKAFrh\/bt3WWv\/lPKrrVtS97UtyOv4OXlJc+MHDVK6h9Rxu3g4ABXV1c5G8b38Hk2ywfwPxl82VUQg+kPAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  is always\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>greater than 4.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>greater than 8.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>greater than 12.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>None of the above\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"b","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu26":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>5<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>6<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the area of the largest possible isosceles triangle, such that its perimeter is 20 cm and the lengths of all its sides (in cm) are integers. \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='29' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAMCAYAAABx290PAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJBSURBVDhPrZS9S7JhFMYDV5cGBRdDkaChIUhSENT\/IGxoEcIKJQVxMhClzSwkEAtCCgcHqbbyC0PCf0BxUFCbRERQSB0MVLrinB717aWa\/MED55z75j7X+dAl\/MHt7S0cDsdCvz8T7u3t4eXlZaHfrwkTiQR8Pp\/gLY5fE56cnCCVSrHd7XZxd3eHi4sLPD4+cmxKo9FALBaD3+9HOp0WonMeHh5wdXWFer3O\/o8JJ5MJ9vf3MRgMMBwOIZPJ4PV6kcvlsL6+DpfLxfeq1SrEYjFubm6QTCbZDoVCfEa43W4cHx8jm81CpVKh2Wz+nLBcLsPpdLL9\/v7Oj005PT3F6uoq251OZ9YFgkQaDAa2qSKpVMqiie3tbXg8HizVajVWcnZ2xgcEtSASiQjenFarBb1ez9v7E1tbW7N3aAQrKytsE8FgEEajEUuFQoEfWF5eRr\/f58OjoyNUKhW2p9BMlUoldnd3hch3Li8vWcx4PGY\/EAhAq9WyTYTDYeh0unlL19bW+NLHxwcODg6E6Byq7vX1FRqNBhaLRYh+QbOl6trtthABrq+voVAoBO9LELV7lvD+\/p6TPj098cb9RiaTgUgk4tkStKUkggT9C81dIpEI3leHbDbb96XZ3NyEXC5HsVgUIsDb2xsODw9nw6dt3djY4E0ejUasmgRS9c\/Pz3yX6PV6vN1UPaFWq5HP578njMfjnPB\/rFYr\/y1Fo1FesOmsSYzJZOIkZrMZOzs7OD8\/5zOiVCrBbrfzItFPBwA+ASRkQl0WNL0tAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  sq. cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='29' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAMCAYAAABx290PAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAI\/SURBVDhPrZK9S7JRGMb7FxwUXJTQQSeHPjBI0MDdTSklsSFKdDRQJFz8ADe1QGoJNKpJFIdIwkUowXRQSMFJcFEhQ3EQr\/c9t0ee195q8gcHzn2d85zrnPu51vAL19fXcDqdKx2\/Gh4eHuL5+Xml40fDXC4Hv9\/Pq9Xxo+H5+Tny+TzNe70eHh4eEIlEkEqlSPtKt9vFzc0NrwTYd4lEAq1Wi+pvDafTKRwOB4bDIcbjMSQSCXw+H56eniCXy3F8fMx3ChiNRkilUl7N8Xg8ODs7w+PjI5RKJTqdzveG9Xodbreb5pPJBJlMhuaMi4uL\/w5mr9bpdNjb2+MK6EXsouzSDJPJBK\/Xi7Vms0k3Ye1awFqQTCZ5tQwLks1m4xXQbrdhsVjo9dvb21wF7u7uqBsLotEoDAYD1iqVCsVfJBLh4+ODFk9OTtBoNGj+L+xQlUpF\/3SB3W5HtVrF+\/s7Njc3uQqEQiHs7OzwCojFYtjd3RVaqlarEQ6HMZvNcHR0xFUBduDGxgbYBRdcXl5Cq9WiWCxShzQaDSX79fUV6XQa6+vrfCcQj8eh1+sFw\/v7ezLNZrMIBoNcnTMajagdpVKJK6CLvby80H6WxEAgAIVCQUb9fp+CIhaL+e556lnYlkLDWiKTyfD29saVOSyxbLD\/VS6XYbVaMRgM+Ooc1m5muICts3AVCgWqt7a2qBNLhre3t2T4lYODAzJkYTGbzXC5XHxFgIVsf38fn5+fXAFqtRpOT0+p3VdXV38V4A84ckQNqgr2RAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  sq. cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='29' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAMCAYAAABx290PAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJlSURBVDhPrZTNS3JREMaDQAgCaWHYpkhEaSEoKCgE1X8QbVpGWooV4UpBFHdqEG0yF1G0iihX9kUoEW7cCH1AhlgLURGEQDRSxOh5mfGU1Fut\/MHlzjzncmbOzJzbgz\/Y3d3F8vJyV58\/A87NzeHq6qqrz68BT09P4fV6hdc9fg3o8\/lwfn7O9vPzMw4PD7GxsYHj42PWvpPP5xEKhXB7eyuUNpFIBFtbW3h8fGT\/x4Bvb28wm82o1Wqo1+sYGhqCx+PB5eUlNBoNHA6H+LLN\/v4+ZmZmsLOzg1wuJ1TA6XTC5XIhFotBqVSiWCz+HDCdTmN1dZXtRqOBs7MztolAIACVSiU8IB6PQ61W4\/X1VSht6ESDg4OcNDE9PQ23242ebDbLmaytrfECQSXY3t4WXodSqYSJiQmeXqLVakGr1WJvbw+0T6FQYJ2gFoyMjAgPWF9fx9TUFHqur695g4GBAVSrVV602+14eHhg+wPqqUKhwOzsrFCAp6cnSCQSTphOrtPpEAwGeY3eJpOJbWJzcxPj4+Odko6NjfFH7+\/vsFgsQu1Ap6MARqMR8\/PzrJ2cnEAqlaJcLrOfTCbR19fHbaBTj46Osk7QQE1OTnYCHh0dcVDaxO\/3C\/V\/Li4u0Nvby3YqleKBoiQJqlB\/fz8nR3dOJpOxTlCFbDbb16HR6\/UYHh7Gzc2NUIBKpYKFhYXP5tO0UukI0uRy+edQRaNR7luz2cTLywsnQ5NNGAwGJBKJrwEPDg444HesViv\/lqhM1K+PXhP39\/dYWVlBOBzG4uIiMpmMWAHu7u6wtLTEA0lXBgD+AYuvPr7yOrwsAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  sq. cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='29' Height= '12' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABwAAAAMCAYAAABx290PAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJXSURBVDhPrZQ\/SLJRFMYDcZNIcAmkwSEoaigdnHRqcAoicBFCk0DDaDEIFIUgS6ghcFCSAkXRzVIRIQqKosCEoMQ\/s5MoKdRQ+cQ5vVp+Xzb5gxfOOfd973Pvc44O4Q+CwSBWV1cH+vwpuLS0hPPz84E+fQWTySScTqeQDY6+gi6XC+l0muNarYZYLIb9\/X2cnJxwrcPHxwcikQgODg5wfX0tVL8oFArclq2tLdze3nLtV8H393eYTCY0m028vLxgdHQUDocDZ2dnmJ6exvr6Or9Ha3Nzc\/B4PLi4uIBSqUQ4HOY1cmh4eBiJRAKhUAhisRh3d3e\/Cz4+PmJtbY3j19dXpFIpjgnafHx8nGPaaHJykmOC8qmpKbTbbZTLZT5Eh9nZWWxvb2OoVCphY2MDu7u7whLg8\/kQCASE7JtqtQqtVss2EfSNSqXimMjlcpDJZHzIn5DtcrkcNzc3GLq\/v+cNpFIpnp+f+QWLxYKnpyeOO1BPFQoF9Hq9UAGKxSIkEgmOj49ZzGazYWRkhK3+idVqhdFo5Lhr6cTEBHZ2dtiO5eVlofoN3a5SqUCtVnc\/Ji4vL7nffr8fm5ubbDHNQIfDw0PodDq8vb1x3hWMx+Msenp6yl73I5PJQCQS\/Wcbsbi4CLvdLmTA1dUVNBqNkH3RMzTUj7GxMeTzeaECNBoNmM1mnliCpnVmZqbnFnR6agtt3mq1uFav1\/m29HMi62mgvF5vr2A0GmXBf1lZWeG\/paOjIx6wTq8JEnO73djb2xMqXzw8PGBhYYEPazAYMD8\/j2w2i099ckdeRu5e4gAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  sq. cm\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"c","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu27":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>What is the remainder when \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>(1<sup>1<\/sup> + 2<sup>2<\/sup> + 3<sup>3<\/sup> + 4<sup>4<\/sup> + 5<sup>5<\/sup> + 6<sup>6<\/sup> + 7<sup>7<\/sup> + 8<sup>8<\/sup> + 9<sup>9<\/sup>) + (10<sup>9<\/sup> \u2013 11<sup>8<\/sup> + 12<sup>7<\/sup> \u2013 13<sup>6<\/sup> + 14<sup>5<\/sup> \u2013 15<sup>4<\/sup> + 16<sup>3<\/sup> \u2013 17<sup>2<\/sup> + 18<sup>1<\/sup>) is divided by 19?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"0","CORRECT_ANSWER":"0","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu28":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>There are 40 students in a class. Each student had three electives to choose from \u2013 Physics, Chemistry and Mathematics. Ten students chose Physics, 15 chose Chemistry, 20 chose Mathematics, two chose all the three, five chose Physics and Chemistry, four chose Physics and Mathematics but not Chemistry, one chose Chemistry and Mathematics but not Physics. How many students did not choose any of the three subjects? \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"7","CORRECT_ANSWER":"7","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu29":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>7<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>2<\/i><i>9<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>How many positive integral solutions of <i>x<\/i>, <i>y<\/i> and <i>z<\/i> exist for the equation <i>x<\/i> + <i>y<\/i> + <i>z<\/i> = 10, so that no two of the three quantities are equal?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"24","CORRECT_ANSWER":"24","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu30":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The product of 114 and 21 in a certain number system is 2444. Find the decimal equivalent of the number represented as 4231 in that number system.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>566\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>1398\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>944\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>676\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu31":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>If five dice are thrown simultaneously, what is the probability of getting the sum as seven?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='17' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAdCAYAAABMr4eBAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAMiSURBVEhLzZVdSFNhGMcneiEDP1AvUrOPoVG2mbApThT0oraZzW5EIbtN04V9UIGBYGYLFXehDT\/SiwpDvVK7cG4XiWJioEFOyQvBTLtwaqBufv97z7P3zJyp5EX0gwfO\/3ne9897nnPOcyTwwtLTg5KSJ1y5WVxcgNlshtFoREVFhSdmZ2epvsfEPjaG8PATiL0o5xk3n4aHIZFIkJiYiPT0dE\/Mzf2gOplsbmzgWXk5LRRCEXeJiiLlT8vg6+vL1X7IxG63IyQkBM3NLcjQ6RAVdZqKIjqtBgpFHCYnv8JqtWJqaopX3JCJ0+nE6uoqJa5mZCAi4iRdC2xtbUF29gz8\/PzYrYZDKpXSaZ8bX\/AVXj0R0Gm1iIyM4gpYWlpip5AjOzsb09PfWJMXcbe4mIy6u9\/TmiNN\/oTTuUomRYY7pI80WVhwoL29HfPzDp4B1tZcZHIrv4D0kSafR0dpQ8HtQp4Buru6KPf6zVvS+0yS1Wr4+0u5clOQn0+b9Ho9cnNz+XUWtre3qb7PpK2tDbW1dVzt0tLSTCZarQ4NjY0862afyXH4j0wsFgv7akuOHaWlpZBMTExAMDoqent7YbPZPCFoMf9ve2J+WUfzJC0tjcJqtfHKX5gkJqjw8NFjLC8vw+FwYGVlhVe8TD4ODrKXSQuZTIaUlBT09FgoLwyt0NBQ5OXlUTP7BwYoL+IxEUdgUpIaJpMJKqWSdH\/\/AM2a1NRUGAwGlJWVITAwEE1Nr\/jO30yS1Ulsop3iig2jzU3Ex8ejvr6BZ3Z5cP8eTToRMtlhH5KPjw+qqqvxfWYGHR0dGBoaogUCoyMjUKlUbCAtkb6WmYnLVzR0LUAmP9n0EsafRqNBUFAQgoOD6VZycnKxvrZOt6Njs1cuVyCTGURHx+AL+zOIkMk4G9TCJmF+Co\/O5XLhXWsr5Sorq2ihQF\/fB3R2du55MgJk4nDM0wbvn9a5mBgolSquDsbd2J0d6klhkYGkSOyF81CqErg6GLcJ43qWHhJmZB8fJ22zWel0NTUm0ofhMXGy5gmvc1hYGNRsRAYEBOBG3k1ePQzgF34oRv\/\/h5RyAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='15' Height= '26' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAAA8AAAAaCAYAAABozQZiAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAJiSURBVDhPzZTPT5JxHMcBJwfyIozFxobd+Qfsgo4rGOPKbIssYWNamY2TaOOiyKqtukAiYltuQatMoCMqelBcssAmjBMnpiiELLi8e55PD4+xh1qurfXePtvzeX++r+\/v7yNCBzmdThwe5risXQ9nZpBIrNO3ALaNjkIsFiN7cMA555qbnYVEIkE48oZyHn7\/7i3UajVUKhW6urqwtb3NVYDdnR1otVooFApIpVIsBpfI5+Enjx\/B45nH\/v4n6j2Z3OIqQCQSweTkAxSLRUi7u+Hz+ckXTDuT+QyRSNQGt3R2VqOaz\/+CcgHMjvwr+OSkDPH\/Ce\/tpQhuneXPKpePqfb02XPKBXC5XEYoFEKpVOKcczUaDaod5n5cIAF8Ef0dzE4zn89fOAqFAkThcBg2m+23Ybfb24L1HA7HP1jzy+VlmEwmmM1milwuT\/4fwVf7+zE15WLufQap1C6q1Sr5bXA8FoPRaIROp6MXxqrR+Ibe3l4MD1+nl5VOp8lnxcMrK6\/o9tybmIDX66XvG9abaDabNNU5jwdutxsymQwbG5vE8LBKdRm3bo9yGbAUDGJo6BoqlSrq9TrnAgMDOtxnZsCK4K\/MGtiR\/MyFn3a5YLVasbYWpQbsQ+np6UE0GsP6eoKWEI9\/pBrBX5j\/lUQsgVwuh8ViwcjICHU25ZqmRoGFBQwODkKv1yMQWCSPFQ+zjcfGxslkNe+ZI+\/o6JhzhCK4Ujmlhq\/DETJZJZOb5LXOtJP4DbvS18cc0QCXAXfvjDM7ewm12hnnCMXD2WwWGo0GBoOB1q1UKrG6+oGrdhLwHdIqDQmWIu\/xAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='16' Height= '28' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABAAAAAcCAYAAABoMT8aAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAAMXSURBVEhLvZRdSFNhHMY38QtUNMQJTgODmh91o16moIZd5YUGphaKWBN3pV5oLM0yUC\/SLtxkal9OWBopG0jO0KASTRx4t5mGzq\/cwISJH4jz6bz\/82rODMugB144z\/N\/z++c877\/80pwRLW1tfjw4SN3opaWFlFVWQmVSgVtayt2d3d5BfAAaDQt8PLyQm9vH08At9uNxIQExMTEoKioCEFBQSgtVfEqB9jtdqSlpkIikdDQ67uoyHS3qooyh8NJvkvfSf7TyAh5AvR0dyMj4yreDw9DKpXi+YuXVGSKFZ6clpbOHbCzswN\/f39U19wnT4C9vT0yiwsLRD8MkEdEoKCgkDtRMlkY8vLy6dpjDb5MTf0CiIqUo7y8gjtRsrAw5OTcoOsTAZFyObKysrkT3\/ZMSAhu31GSPxFwJT1N2IFY7oTPXBQ\/U9fWRt4DMGWzUbHj6TOeAH29byhraGzE3OwsMjOvwcfHBysrDqp7AL7OzAgLJIPhVTdPRLEmYv3h5+eH4OBg9PS85pUjANY0LpeLtuqoFoQdmpycxNraGk9EeQBOo38HOJ1OWCyWUw9Jf3+\/0CjlKCsr++vB7vs\/a7C5uYknzc1Qq9U0evt+\/u5\/BHg3aEZgYBDahO7TarUYMJt55QiA9fmgUDQYDLAJXbmvR3V1SExKgslkgtVq5amoAwBroJSUZDoPQkNDqX012laq3bqZj+jocyguLkaE8HvX8LOA6QBQWFBAN9tsU3ALZ9717GyCLC9\/w\/fVVVoHJvPAW\/j6+GKDewKwG6RSCeobGilkYu1sHhjA+vo6SkpKMDQ0TLnJaERAQAC2trbJE8DpcNDT6+sb6GyMiopCbm6eMGmLJj18UCv8RCFQKpVC7SweNzVRzkQAy8QEAby9vVFeUQGdTofwcBmdAy7XOk0cHR2lXRgfHye\/LwLMTE\/T96rvVVPI9HlsjDKj0cST40WAbeFV2eT29g4Kmez2Oco6O\/U8OV4EYLp0MR7nLyiwsSGuLtt7BrAe6ofjdABYmJ9HfFwcFAoFkpMv08HZotHw6u8E\/ACN269Y\/Lr8ngAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <img Width='17' Height= '29' style = \"vertical-align:middle;\" src=\"data:image\/jpg;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAABEAAAAdCAYAAABMr4eBAAAAAXNSR0IArs4c6QAAAARnQU1BAACxjwv8YQUAAAAJcEhZcwAADsMAAA7DAcdvqGQAAALsSURBVEhLzZRdSFNhGMdnaSj4keY0LEGEsgQvRGpQW9GaCgYG1ZX5mQaKFYa6afmxGzHBKx1GdeFMu3GWqwymC7GbxFATN8EuRLekBfsQA8WW8u\/s2bu55dn6uOoHL5zn\/5z3d97zng8BAvBmZATV1dV+Qy6Xs64\/ASWlJcWIjIxEbm6ud1RWVbGuP7ySnZ0dJAiFKC4pZUlweCUWiwUCgQAPOjqg1Wqh0Whgs9lZdy+8ktFRHUmioqKQmpqKiIgI7jgaw5yQD16JfmwMYrEYmqEhqh12O8RnzyAs7ABWV1cp8yXgxv7Ku4kJWl3\/wDOW7MIrmZ2dweDgIKvczM7MkETd95Qlu\/BK7ty+RRMMRiNLAHl9PWVGn8wDr8R138nJRxEdE4Pm5mYUFBSQoKHxHjvDn4B78tlsRlVlJTIzMyGRSNDfP8A6e\/njjQ3GfyRZWlqCXq\/\/5zE+Pg6BTqdDS0vLb0d7ezs6Ozu9o62tjXKlUvnnt7OxsQGDwYDp6Wka6+vfWOcv9uRyfj4SEhKRlZVFQ61Wsw6PZHNzE8vLy7DabCxx\/19SUlLw6vUIS\/zxk6hUKsTFxSE8PJz7YsNQV1dP+VfLF4TuD0VOTg794VpblZR78EpePB+iV7um5i7m5+fR1HSf6kePn8BkWqE3V63uw+Tke\/rr1dbWsZk+krTjx3DqtIhVboqLitDdrWLVLt1dXUhMPMwqJtna2qKrdnET3nLPXqFQoKfnIZ3g4qV2GGLu+\/FQUX7D74IkcTjs2BcSgoyMDAjjhRCJRCRNSzsBM\/chWq1WpKefhEwmQ1lZGbeKRExNfSCBC5KsrTkQwk2K5wQmk5kanxYXKbteWEi10\/kd6t5e2vyVFRNlHtwSh4OurGhopNDDRekF7mkdwo\/tbZbwQxKn00m3U15xk0IP589JkJR0BNvcexIMkri4dvUKrca4sED13NxHqn0fZSC8km1uydnZMm5f4iGVShEbexB5eZdYNxjAT1\/gd50Iz+yrAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC\"\/>  \n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"a","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu32":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>0<\/i><i> <\/i><i>t<\/i><i>o<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>2<\/i><i>:<\/i> Select the correct alternative from the given choices.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The sum of ten consecutive integers is half the sum of the next five consecutive integers. What is the sum of all the 15 integers?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>120\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT2":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>180\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT3":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>60\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT4":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>75\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","CORRECT_ANSWER":"d","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"7","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"1","TIME":"0"},"qu33":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>The monthly expenditure incurred by a hostel comprises a fixed component and a variable component, which varies with the number of persons living in the hostel. If there are 100 persons, the average monthly expenditure per person is Rs.2400. If there are 200 persons, the average monthly expenditure per person is Rs.2200. What is the fixed component of the monthly expenditure (in Rs.) of the hostel?\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"40000","CORRECT_ANSWER":"40000","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"},"qu34":{"ENGLISH":{"QUESTION_TEXT":"<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'> <b>D<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>R<\/b><b>E<\/b><b>C<\/b><b>T<\/b><b>I<\/b><b>O<\/b><b>N<\/b><b>S<\/b><b> <\/b><i>f<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>r<\/i><i> <\/i><i>q<\/i><i>u<\/i><i>e<\/i><i>s<\/i><i>t<\/i><i>i<\/i><i>o<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>s<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>3<\/i><i> <\/i><i>a<\/i><i>n<\/i><i>d<\/i><i> <\/i><i>3<\/i><i>4<\/i><i>:<\/i> Type in your answer in the input box provided below the question.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9;'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>A function f(x) is defined on the interval 0 \u2264 x \u2264 2 as below:\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>f(x)    = integer closest to x, if x \u2260 0.5 or 1.5.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>f(0.5) = 1\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>f(1.5) = 2\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n<span><p style='vertical-align:middle;'> <font style='Color:black;font-family:Arial;size:9'><font style='font-family:Arial;'>Find the area (in sq.units) under the graph of this function and above the x-axis, bound by the lines x = 0 and x = 2.\n<\/font>\n<\/font><\/p><\/span>\n","OPT1":"2","CORRECT_ANSWER":"2","UNIT":"","SOLUTION":"-na-","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"HINDI":{"QUESTION_TEXT":" ","CORRECT_ANSWER":" ","UNIT":" ","SOLUTION":"","ESSAY_ID":"0","EASSY_DETAILS":" ","ESSAY_NAME":"ESSAY_NAME"},"SUBJECT_ID":"3","TOPIC_ID":" 140","QUESTION_TYPE":"2","RIGHT_MARKS":"3","WRONG_MARKS":"0","TIME":"0"}}